<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright (C) 2011-2012, Dirk Trossen, airs@dirk-trossen.de
  Copyright (C) 2013, TecVis LP, support@tecvis.co.uk

  This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it
  under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License as published by
  the Free Software Foundation as version 2.1 of the License.

  This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT
  ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY
  or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU Lesser General Public
  License for more details.

  You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public License
  along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software Foundation, Inc.,
  59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA 02111-1307 USA 
 -->
<resources>
<string name="app_name">AIRS</string>
<string name="Copyright">&#169; 2004-2006 Nokia Corp.\n&#169; 2008-2012 Dirk Trossen; \n&#169; 2013-2014 TecVis LP
\n\nContact: dot@tecvis.co.uk
\n\nFollow Us on Twitter at @tecvis
\n\nFacebook: http://www.facebook.com/tecvisuk
\n\nManual: http://tecvis.co.uk/software-2/airs/
\n\nAIRS source code is licensed under LGPL 2.0 license and hosted on Github. For more information on license terms, review <b>license.txt</b>!
\n\nSpecial acknowledgment goes to Dana Pavel. Using AIRS for her research work (http://dalore.me.uk/Dana/research-areas) has provided many opportunities to introduce new features (such as event and mood button) as well as improve AIRS in terms of stability and features!
\n\nNOTE that the authors assume no responsibility for any potential misuse of this software for spying purposes. The operation is exposed through notification bar icons in order to make users aware of ongoing recordings!
</string>
<string name="tab_Record">Record</string>
<string name="tab_Config">Config</string>
<string name="tab_Sync">Sync</string>
<string name="tab_Visualise">Visualise</string>
<string name="main_About">About</string>
<string name="main_Sync">Synchronising Recordings</string>
<string name="Help">Help</string>
<string name="recording_prompt">Type of Recording</string>
<string name="main_Configure">General Settings</string>
<string name="main_Configure2">Set general application settings such as server IP, watchdog information and others.</string>
<string name="GeneralSettings">\'Server\' defines the address of the AIRS application server (must be public), followed by the port.\n\n
\'Local Display\' toggles the output of sensor values in local sensing\n\n
\'Local Storage\' switches the local storage on/off in local sensing. \n\n
\'Sensor History\' determines the number of sensor values being shown in the AIRS visualisations.\n\n
\'Wakeup\' only senses in local mode when there is any other (user) activity, i.e., it does not hold a wake-lock.\n\n
\'Reminder Interval\' defines the vibration and LED notification interval for the local sensing watchdog (0 switches the vibrate off)\n\n
\'Debug\' switches the debug output on/off. \n</string>
<string name="MapAbout">Shows a path of recent GPS recording. You can click on a marker for more information. You can center the map either on your current location or the last stored one (using the buttons on the top right). You can also switch between map or satellite view with the appropriate options menu item.</string>
<string name="ManualAbout">Shows the AIRS online manual.\nYou will need  Internet access for the page to show. You can click on links to various manual chapters like on any other webpage. Use the BACK key to navigate back to higher levels or exit the manual at the main level.</string>
<string name="RecordAbout">Start recording here, selecting the mode of recording you would like.\n\nYou can also load and delete <b>templates</b> that you stored as well as create shortcuts to a selected template on your launcher screen. Clicking on a template will automatically load the template.\n\nInstead of defining your own templates, you can also <b>download</b> examples from the TecVis server.</string>
<string name="LocalAbout">Shows the sensors available in local sensing mode.\nChoose the sensors you would like to record. Through the menu, you can select and unselect all sensors (for a clean sheet) as well as look at the sensor repository, giving you information on type, value ranges etc of the sensors that were discovered.</string>
<string name="ValuesAbout">Shows the current values of the sensors being read in local mode.\nFrom here, you can either <b>Exit</b> the program (and stop the service) or simply stop the display with the <b>BACK</b> key!\nYou can also <b>PAUSE</b> or <b>RESUME</b> the measurement threads (this does not stop the service but halts the recordings only).</string>
<string name="RemoteAbout">Shows the number of values and the bytes being sent in remote mode.\nFrom here, you can either <b>Exit</b> the program (and stop the service) or simply stop the display with the <b>BACK</b> key!</string>
<string name="MoodAbout">Select the mood you are currently in. Your selection is recorded with a timestamp in the <b>MO</b> sensor.\nExit the selector without selection by using the <b>BACK</b> key!\nYou can define your own mood entry in the text field at the bottom.</string>
<string name="EventAbout">Select the type of event you are currently in. Your selection is recorded with a timestamp in the <b>EB</b> sensor.\nExit the selector without selection by using the <b>BACK</b> key!\nYou can define your own event entry in the text field at the bottom. You can delete any entry by long clicking on it and confirming the deletion.\n\nAIRS stores your last defined events persistently.</string>
<string name="TimelineAbout">Shows a historical timeline of the sensor you just clicked on. You can change the number of historical values in the <b>General Settings</b>\nExit the timeline by using the <b>BACK</b> key!</string>
<string name="DBadminAbout">Choose any of the three DB actions, namely <b>Backup</b>, <b>Restore</b> or <b>Index</b>. You can only index the DB once and cannot undo the indexing after it is done.</string>
<string name="SyncAbout">Allows for sharing the data since the last synchronisation as a text file.\n\nYou can also manually set the last sync date, in case you need to re-sync periods.</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPSAbout">This list shows you the most visited WiFi APs over a given period. Only APs that you have connected to will be shown here!</string>
<string name="HandlersList">Select the sensors you want to record as well as configure various available settings for the sensors! You can also configure <b>General Settings</b> for AIRS.</string>
<string name="Sensor_Selection">Sensor Selection</string>
<string name="HandlerDescription">Handler Image</string>
<string name="Online_Manual">Online Manual</string>
<string name="Yes">Yes</string>
<string name="No">No</string>
<string name="OK">OK</string>
<string name="Cancel">Cancel</string>
<string name="Select">Select</string>
<string name="Duration">Duration</string>

<string name="Getting_Started">Getting Started</string>
<string name="Getting_Started2">For local recording:\n
- select \'Lifelogging\' for lifelogging settings\n
- press \'Shortcut\' to place a shortcut on your launcher homescreen\n
- place AIRS event and mood widgets on your homescreen for annotations\n
- adjust settings as you like, e.g., adding WiFi hotspots to your adaptive GPS list!\n
- start \'AIRS local\' recording from your launcher screen with the created shortcut!\n
- for more complex visualisations of your recordings, download our Storica app at http://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.storica\n
- for more information on recording, see http://tecvis.co.uk/software/storica/tips-for-recording\n\n
For remote recording, download the AIRS application server (see on our website) and read the AIRS online manual through the options menu\n
</string>

<string name="ConnectGoogle">Google Account</string>
<string name="ConnectGoogle2">Connect to Google Account for GDrive Backup</string>
<string name="ConnectGoogle3">Wait for connecting to your Google Account!</string>
<string name="ConnectGoogle4">Cannot find Google Account information on this device!</string>
<string name="ConnectGoogle5">You need to grant access for the upload function to work!</string>
<string name="FolderGoogle">Upload Folder</string>
<string name="FolderGoogle2">Select the folder in GDrive root directory to upload to - will be created if it does not exist. This setting is specific for each recording template!</string>
<string name="Cannot_backup">Cannot backup database while AIRS is running!</string>
<string name="Cannot_restore">Cannot restore database while AIRS is running!</string>
<string name="Cannot_create_backup">Cannot create backup file (possible access error or external media does not exist)!</string>
<string name="Finished_backup">Finished backup successfully!</string>
<string name="Backup_recordings">Backup</string>
<string name="Restore_recordings">Restore</string>
<string name="Starting_backup">Starting backup</string>
<string name="Starting_restore">Starting restore</string>
<string name="Backup_status">Backup DB of size</string>
<string name="Restore_status">Restore DB of size</string>
<string name="Index_DB">Database Indexing</string>
<string name="Index_DB_message">Indexing your database greatly improves the performance in retrieving values for visualisation but will increase the size of your database by about 60%! You only need to index once.\n\nDo you want to continue?</string>
<string name="Cannot_index">Cannot index DB file (Possibly indexed already or possible access error or external media does not exist)!</string>
<string name="Cannot_restore2">Cannot restore DB file (Possible access error or external media does not exist)!</string>
<string name="Finished_indexing">Finished indexing successfully!</string>
<string name="Finished_restore">Finished restore successfully!</string>
<string name="sensed">sensed</string>
<string name="sensed2">times\nLast sensing at</string>
<string name="sensed3">with value :\n</string>
<string name="Sensor_invalid">Sensor invalid - Reason:</string>
<string name="Sensor_invalid2">Sensor invalid - Reason: unknown</string>
<string name="Sensor_suspended">Sensor suspended - Reason:</string>
<string name="Sensor_suspended2">Sensor suspended - Reason: unknown</string>
<string name="Enable_at_least_one_sensor">You need to enable at least one sensor before starting the measurements!</string>
<string name="Started_AIRS">Started AIRS</string>
<string name="Stop_AIRS">Stop AIRS</string>
<string name="AIRS_Remote_Sensing">AIRS Remote Sensing</string>
<string name="AIRS_Local_Sensing">AIRS Local Sensing</string>
<string name="AIRS_Sensing">AIRS Sensing</string>
<string name="running_since">&#8230;running since&#8230;</string>
<string name="restarted_since">&#8230;is restarted since&#8230;</string>
<string name="killed_at">&#8230;has been killed at</string>
<string name="AIRS_killed">AIRS killed</string>
<string name="battery">battery</string>
<string name="binding_failed">Binding to service unsuccessful!</string>
<string name="Local_Sensing">Local Sensing</string>
<string name="paused">paused</string>
<string name="Exit_AIRS">Exit will stop your recording and close the background service!\nAre you sure you want to exit?</string>
<string name="Exit_AIRS2">Exit AIRS?</string>
<string name="Snapshot_nothing_to_share">Nothing to share, it seems! Have you set the camera path to the right one (the path need to the SAME as shown for pictures in the Gallery applications!).</string>
<string name="Snapshot_share">Share AIRS snapshot to:</string>
<string name="Snapshot_publish">Published from AIRS</string>
<string name="Snapshot_only_pictures">Can only share pictures, sorry!</string>
<string name="Measurements_share">Share AIRS Measurements via:</string>
<string name="AIRS_running_exit">AIRS has been running.\nDo you want to interrupt the current recording and start over? You will need to start AIRS again.</string>
<string name="AIRS_running_exit2">AIRS has been running.\nDo you want to interrupt the current recording and start over? You will need to start the shortcut again.</string>
<string name="AIRS_started_local">Started AIRS local service!\nYou can see its current view by clicking on the notification bar update.</string>
<string name="Delete_template">Delete Template</string>
<string name="At_least_one_template">You need at least one template being saved AND selected from the list before you can create a shortcut!</string>
<string name="At_least_one_template2">You need at least one template being saved AND selected from the list before you can delete a template!</string>
<string name="Created_shortcut">Created AIRS shortcut on launcher homescreen!</string>
<string name="Configured_airs">Created AIRS template and shortcut on launcher homescreen!</string>
<string name="Configure_AIRS">Configure AIRS&#8230;please wait</string>
<string name="Load_template">Load Template</string>
<string name="Load_template2">Loading the template will override the current settings!\nAre you sure?</string>
<string name="Save_template">Filename to Save Settings as Template</string>
<string name="Saved_settings">Saved template</string>
<string name="Restored_settings">Restored template</string>
<string name="Start_remote_sensing">Are you sure you want to start remote sensing?\n\nAIRS will attempt to connect to the remote application server, blocking the ability to exit the AIRS service until the connection request times out.</string>
<string name="Sensing_not_running">Sensing not running!\nThe service might have crashed!</string>
<string name="Gathering_sensors">Gathering local sensors</string>
<string name="Please_wait">Please wait&#8230;</string>
<string name="Cannot_find_storage">Cannot find external storage!</string>
<string name="Last_sync">Last sync:</string>
<string name="Set_sync_date">Set Sync Date</string>
<string name="Set_sync_date2">You can set the last sync date here (starting at 00:00 in the morning). It will overwrite your current sync timestamp!</string>
<string name="Start_synchronising">Start synchronising</string>
<string name="Interrupt_synchronising">Do you want to interrupt synchronisation?</string>
<string name="Send_local_recordings">Send Local Recordings To:</string>
<string name="No_values_to_synchronise">There are no values to synchronise!</string>
<string name="Regular_sync">You have selected regular uploads in your general settings and can therefore not manually synchronise!</string>
<string name="Temp_sync_file">Temp file (kB):</string>
<string name="Sync_upload">Uploaded recordings!</string>
<string name="Sync_uploading">Uploading recordings</string>
<string name="Sync_progress">Progress :</string>
<string name="AIRS_Map">AIRS Map View</string>
<string name="First_sensing">First sensing at</string>
<string name="First_sensing2">with value :</string>
<string name="Delete_event">Do you want to delete this annotation from the list?</string>
<string name="Camera_error">Cannot open the camera resource!</string>
<string name="Shortcut_not_found">Cannot find the shortcut preference file! Please recreate the shortcut.</string>
<string name="Select_Sensors">Select Sensors</string>
<string name="Select_Sensors2">Select which sensors you would like to record</string>
<string name="AIRS_mood_selection2">Last: </string>
<string name="Recorded_shared_text">Successfully recorded your shared text!</string>
<string name="previous_item">&lt;</string>
<string name="next_item">&gt;</string>
<string name="Timeline_Viewer3">Minimum Time</string>
<string name="Timeline_Viewer4">Maximum Time</string>
<string name="TimeFormat2">%H:%M:%S</string>

<!-- handler UIs -->
 
<string name="AudioHandlerUI_name">Audio Sampling</string>
<string name="AudioHandlerUI_description">Surrounding sound environment (level and frequency)</string>
<string name="AudioHandlerUI_about">Senses the surrounding sound environment.\n\nThe sensor values are frequency or average amplitude of a sound sample.\nThe sampling rate and the polling interval for the sampling can be set in order to optimize the reading and processing requirements.</string>

<string name="BeaconHandlerUI_name">Bluetooth Beacon</string>
<string name="BeaconHandlerUI_description">Surrounding BT devices</string>
<string name="BeaconHandlerUI_about">Senses surrounding Bluetooth devices.\n\nThe sensor values are of the format MAC::name for each discovered device.\nAll service devices are attempted to be discovered so that all discoverable BT devices should  be sensed.\nThe user can be asked to switch on BT if it is switched off before starting the sensing.</string>

<string name="CalendarHandlerUI_name">Calendar</string>
<string name="CalendarHandlerUI_description">Events from your available calendars</string>
<string name="CalendarHandlerUI_about">Retrieves calendar entries from your available calendars!\nYou can select the calendars that AIRS should monitor. The calendars are polled frequently for upcoming events.</string>

<string name="DeviceInfoHandlerUI_name">Device Information</string>
<string name="DeviceInfoHandlerUI_description">Various phone-based information like orientation, proximity, RAM, battery etc</string>
<string name="DeviceInfoHandlerUI_about">Senses various phone-based sensors and system information.\n\nThe orientation is only supported for models with internal compass. Other information includes proximity as well as system information such as battery, RAM and tasks.</string>

<string name="EnvironmentalSensorsHandlerUI_name">Environmental Sensors</string>
<string name="EnvironmentalSensorsHandlerUI_description">Obtains various environmental information, such as light, barometer and weather conditions at current location</string>
<string name="EnvironmentalSensorsHandlerUI_about">Obtains environmental information such as light, barometer, and various weather conditions (temperature, humidity, &#8230;) at the current location through an online weather API.</string>

<string name="EventButtonHandlerUI_name">Event Button</string>
<string name="EventButtonHandlerUI_description">A button widget to mark meaningful events</string>
<string name="EventButtonHandlerUI_about">Allows for marking meaningful events through a homescreen (button) widget.\n\nThe user can input their own meaningful description for the event to be marked.\nAIRS stores the most recently defined descriptions with the maximum number to be stored configurable.</string>

<string name="HeartMonitorHandlerUI_name">Heart Monitor</string>
<string name="HeartMonitorHandlerUI_description">HxM BT Heart rate monitor from Zephyr with pulse and instant speed support</string>
<string name="HeartMonitorHandlerUI_about">Senses heart rate values from Zephyr\n\nYou can enable the heart monitor sensing here as well as select the device to connect to.</string>

<string name="LocationHandlerUI_name">Location</string>
<string name="LocationHandlerUI_description">Various location sources like GPS, Wifi and cell</string>
<string name="LocationHandlerUI_about">Senses location-related information.\n\nThe sensor values are location values, utilizing cell identification info, Wifi beacon information as well as GPS.\ncellID is a simple integer, GPS will give long/lat, and WLAN the MAC address, SSID as well as signal strength of nearby access points. \n\nThe settings allow for selecting the poll intervals for Wifi and GPS. Also, you can force to refresh AGPS information frequently, forcing a download of GPS ephemeral information from the network (only supported on some phones).</string>

<string name="MediaWatcherHandlerUI_name">Media Folders</string>
<string name="MediaWatcherHandlerUI_description">Watch various media folder such as camera, music, &#8230;</string>
<string name="MediaWatcherHandlerUI_about">Watches various media-related folders.\n\nCamera, music and other folders can be watched with respect to creating new files, such as when taking a picture.\nFor setting the right camera folders, go into the Gallery application, display any recent picture you have taken, display the \'Details\' and look for the \'Path\' entry. Select the entire path (before the actual filename) as the path for the camera folder!</string>

<string name="NotificationHandlerUI_name">IM/Spotify Notifications</string>
<string name="NotificationHandlerUI_description">Records notifications from IM programs (currently Skype and Google Talk) and Spotify</string>
<string name="NotificationHandlerUI_about">Captures notifications from certain IM programs as well as from Spotify.\n\nCurrently, Skype and Google Talk are supported. Skype only provides the name of the person you are chatting with, while Google Talk provides name and message.\nSpotify information is recorded as track and artist (album information is not provided by Spotify).\nThe sensor is implemented as a so-called Accessibility service and you need to enable its usage in the system settings (which the settings entry will lead you to).</string>

<!-- buttons and other UI elements -->
<string name="Backup">Backup</string>
<string name="Restore">Restore</string>
<string name="Index">Index</string>
<string name="Puls">Puls:</string>
<string name="Select_template_and_action">Select Template and Action</string>
<string name="Delete">Delete</string>
<string name="Shortcut">Shortcut</string>
<string name="Download">Download</string>
<string name="Values"># Values:</string>
<string name="transferred">kBytes transferred :</string>
<string name="Sync_hint">If you want to re-sync, set sync date from the Options menu!</string>
<string name="Save_as_Template">Save as Template</string>
<string name="Pause">Pause</string>
<string name="Resume">Resume</string>
<string name="Exit">Exit</string>
<string name="Select_all">Select All</string>
<string name="Unselect_all">Unselect All</string>
<string name="Info">Info</string>
<string name="DB_Admin">DB Admin</string>
<string name="Manual">Manual</string>
<string name="Rate">Rate AIRS</string>
<string name="Map_View">Map View</string>
<string name="Satellite_View">Satellite View</string>
<string name="Toggle_Path">Toggle Path</string>
<string name="Set_Sync_Date">Set Sync Date</string>
<string name="Back">Back</string>
<string name="Forward">Forward</string>

<!-- general settings preference elements -->
<string name="General_Settings">AIRS General Settings</string>
<string name="Remote_Settings">AIRS Remote Settings</string>
<string name="Address_server">Address of your AIRS application server</string>
<string name="Server_name">Server name</string>
<string name="Port_server">Port of your AIRS application server</string>
<string name="Port_number">Port number</string>
<string name="Local_Settings">AIRS Local Settings</string>
<string name="Local_Display">Local Display</string>
<string name="Local_Display_on">Display sensor values you subscribed to</string>
<string name="Local_Display_off">Do not display sensor values, only number of values sensed</string>
<string name="Local_Storage">Local Storage</string>
<string name="Local_Storage_on">Store sensor values in internal SQLlite database</string>
<string name="Local_Storage_off">Do not store sensor values</string>
<string name="Sync_Settings">Synchronisation Settings</string>
<string name="UploadFrequency">Upload Frequency</string>
<string name="UploadFrequency_on">Set the frequency of uploading recordings to GDrive (or not at all)</string>
<string name="Upload_Wifi">Upload via Wifi only</string>
<string name="AIRS_intents">AIRS Intents</string>
<string name="AIRS_intents_on">Send system intents to allow for, e.g., external rule engine such as AIRS Ruler</string>
<string name="AIRS_intents_off">Do not send system intents</string>
<string name="Wakeup">Wakeup</string>
<string name="Wakeup_on">Wakeup phone during sensing only when there is other user activity</string>
<string name="Wakeup_off">Keep wake lock to prevent sleeping</string>
<string name="Battery_kill">Battery Kill Condition [%]</string>
<string name="Battery_kill_on">Kill AIRS based on battery level to conserve some spare battery (0 = disable)</string>
<string name="Reminder_Settings">Reminder Settings</string>
<string name="Reminder_Interval">Reminder Interval [s]</string>
<string name="Reminder_Interval_on">Interval for reminder that AIRS is running (0 = disable)</string>
<string name="Vibrate">Vibrate</string>
<string name="Vibrate_on">Vibrate as a reminder</string>
<string name="Vibrate_off">Do not vibrate</string>
<string name="Lights">Lights</string>
<string name="Lights_on">Use notification LED as a reminder</string>
<string name="Lights_off">Do not use notification LED as a reminder</string>
<string name="Color_Code">LED Color</string>
<string name="Color_Code_on">Color of LED notification</string>
<string name="Debug">Debug</string>
<string name="Debug_on">Write debug messages in AIRS_debug.txt</string>
<string name="Debug_off">Do not debug anything</string>

<!-- handler settings preference elements -->
<string name="Sampling_Rate">Sampling Rate [Hz]</string>
<string name="Sampling_Rate_on">Sampling rate for audio capture in Hertz</string>
<string name="Choose_Sampling_Rate">Choose Sampling Rate</string>
<string name="Audio_Interval">Audio Interval [s]</string>
<string name="Audio_Interval_on">Interval to wait after each audio capture in seconds</string>
<string name="Sound_Adjustment">Sound Pressure Adjustment [dB]</string>
<string name="Sound_Adjustment_on">Adjustment in dB for Sounds Pressure Level</string>
<string name="Enable_BT">Enable BT</string>
<string name="Enable_BT_on">Programmatically enable BT, if switched off</string>
<string name="Enable_BT_off">Do not enable BT</string>
<string name="Ask_before_enabling">Ask before enabling</string>
<string name="Ask_before_enabling_on">Requests user permission when enabling BT</string>
<string name="Ask_before_enabling_off">Switch on BT without explicit user permission</string>
<string name="BT_Interval">BT Interval [s]</string>
<string name="BT_Interval_on">Poll interval for BT scanning in seconds</string>
<string name="Calendar_Selection">Calendar Selection</string>
<string name="Calendar_Selection_on">Choose the calendars that you want to have watched</string>
<string name="Calendar_Selection_title">Choose Calendars</string>
<string name="Orientation_Interval">Orientation Interval [s]</string>
<string name="Orientation_Interval_on">Poll interval for orientation sensor in seconds</string>
<string name="Proximity_Interval">Proximity Interval [s]</string>
<string name="Proximity_Interval_on">Poll interval for proximity sensor in seconds</string>
<string name="System_Poll_Interval">System Poll Interval [s]</string>
<string name="System_Poll_Interval_on">Poll interval for system information like RAM, tasks, etc</string>
<string name="Sensor_Interval">Sensor Interval [s]</string>
<string name="Sensor_Interval_on">Poll interval for light and barometer sensor in seconds</string>
<string name="Weather_Interval">Weather Interval [min]</string>
<string name="Weather_Interval_on">Poll interval for weather update in minutes</string>
<string name="GPS_Accuracy">GPS Accuracy [m]</string>
<string name="GPS_Accuracy_on">Update weather when moved more than a certain distance (or always)</string>
<string name="GPS_Accuracy_on2">Update accuracy for GPS location in meters</string>
<string name="GPS_Accuracy_title">Update Distance</string>
<string name="Event_Descriptions">Event Descriptions [1..50]</string>
<string name="Event_Descriptions_on">Maximum number of event descriptions to be stored</string>
<string name="Sort_Annotations">Sort Annotations</string>
<string name="Sort_Annotations_on">Sort annotation texts in list that shows after selecting the annotation widget</string>
<string name="Sort_Annotations_off">Do not sort annotation texts in list that shows after selecting the annotation widget</string>
<string name="Enable_Heartmonitor">Enable Heartmonitor</string>
<string name="Enable_Heartmonitor_on">Use heart monitor, attempting to connect at start of discovery</string>
<string name="Enable_Heartmonitor_off">Do not use heartmonitor</string>
<string name="Enable_QSensor">Enable Q Sensor</string>
<string name="Enable_qsensor_on">Use Q sensor, attempting to connect at start of discovery</string>
<string name="Enable_qsensor_off">Do not use Q sensor</string>
<string name="Device_Selection">Device Selection</string>
<string name="Device_Selection_on">Choose one of the possible devices to connect to. You first need to pair with the device in the BT system settings! Make sure the device is switched on when starting AIRS.</string>
<string name="Device_Selection_title">Choose Device</string>
<string name="Averaging_Window">Averaging Window</string>
<string name="Averaging_Window_on">Time window for averaging the pulse measurements, smoothening the values and reducing the numbers of recordings.</string>
<string name="Averaging_Window_title">Choose Window [s]</string>
<string name="Enable_GPS">Enable GPS</string>
<string name="Enable_GPS_on">Enable GPS to show up in sensor list</string>
<string name="Enable_GPS_off">Do not use GPS</string>
<string name="Use_Network_Location">Use Network Location</string>
<string name="Use_Network_Location_on">Use Wifi and network information for location</string>
<string name="Use_Network_Location_off">Use only GPS</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPS">Adaptive GPS</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPS_on">Use Wifi data to temporarily switch off GPS for better battery life. This might lead to delays in locating you once leaving WiFi zones since GPS will need to be re-started.</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPS_off">Do not use WiFi information to temporarily switch off GPS for better battery life</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPS_Selection">WiFi Selection</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPS_Selection_on">Choose the WiFi access points in which proximity GPS recording will be switched off. You will need to subscribe to the WI sensor for this setting to have an effect.</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPS_Hitlist">Most visited WiFis</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPS_Hitlist_on">Shows you the most visited WiFis in a given period so that you can optimise your adaptive GPS.</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPS_Hitlist_Click">Long click on any entry in the list to see how often you visited this WiFi access point.</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPS_Selection_title">Choose WiFi</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPS_NoWifi">Connect to at least one WiFi!</string>
<string name="AdaptiveGPS_NothingFound">Cannot find recent recordings for WiFi - record the WI sensor for some time!</string>
<string name="GPS_Interval">GPS Interval [s]</string>
<string name="GPS_Interval_on">Poll interval for GPS location in seconds</string>
<string name="AGPS_Refresh_Interval">AGPS Refresh Interval [h]</string>
<string name="AGPS_Refresh_Interval_on">Interval to force AGPS refresh in hours (0 = disable)</string>
<string name="Enable_WiFi">Enable WiFi</string>
<string name="Enable_WiFi_on">Programmatically enable WiFi, if switched off</string>
<string name="Enable_WiFi_off">Do not enable WiFi, if switched off</string>
<string name="Prevent_WiFi_Sleep">Prevent WiFi Sleep</string>
<string name="Prevent_WiFi_Sleep_on">Prevent WiFi from sleeping (keeps wake-lock!)</string>
<string name="Prevent_WiFi_Sleep_off">Let WiFi sleep according to system settings</string>
<string name="WiFi_Interval">WiFi Interval [s]</string>
<string name="WiFi_Interval_on">Poll interval for WiFi scanning in seconds</string>
<string name="Enable_Accessibility">Enable Accessibility</string>
<string name="Enable_Accessibility_on">Jumps to System settings to enable the accessibility service required for capturing the IM notifications.</string>
<string name="accessibility_description">Accessibility service for AIRS local sensing, providing access to the Google Talk and Skype notifications through the NO sensor. It also supports Spotify song changes through the MP/MA/MT sensors.</string>
<string name="accessibility_spotify">&#8212;</string>

<string name="Camera">Camera</string>
<string name="Camera_on">Watch camera folder</string>
<string name="Camera_off">Do not watch camera folder</string>
<string name="Camera_Default">Camera Path</string>
<string name="Camera_Default_on">Use system default camera folder</string>
<string name="Camera_Default_off">Define your own camera folder</string>
<string name="Camera_path">Provide camera path</string>
<string name="Camera_path_on">Select picture from camera directory</string>
<string name="Camera_path_select">Select a picture from the camera directory to determine the correct camera path!</string>
<string name="Camera_path_select2">Could not retrieve the path! Did you select a picture that resides on the device?</string>

<string name="Pictures">Pictures</string>
<string name="Pictures_on">Watch pictures folder</string>
<string name="Pictures_off">Do not watch pictures folder</string>
<string name="Pictures_path">Pictures path</string>
<string name="Pictures_path_on">Provide the path for pictures</string>

<string name="Videos">Video</string>
<string name="Videos_on">Watch videos folder</string>
<string name="Videos_off">Do not watch videos folder</string>
<string name="Videos_path">Videos path</string>
<string name="Videos_path_on">Provide the path for videos</string>

<string name="Music">Music</string>
<string name="Music_on">Watch music folder</string>
<string name="Music_off">Do not watch music folder</string>
<string name="Music_path">Music path</string>
<string name="Music_path_on">Provide the path for music</string>

<string name="AF_d">Ambient Frequency</string>
<string name="AF_e">Provides the estimated audio frequency, determining the sound pitch. Measured in Hz.</string>
<string name="AS_d">Ambient Noise Level</string>
<string name="AS_e">Provides the estimated noise level, measured in dB.</string>
<string name="BT_d">Surrounding BT Devices</string>
<string name="BT_e">Provides information about the BT devices around, such as MACs and BT names.</string>
<string name="BN_d"># surrounding BT Devices</string>
<string name="BN_e">Provides the number of BT devices around.</string>
<string name="BD_d">Connected BT Devices</string>
<string name="BD_e">Provides the BT device(s) the phone is connected to.</string>
<string name="BP_d">Blood pressure</string>
<string name="BP_e">Provides blood pressure values that are annotated by the user through the blood pressure phone widget.</string>
<string name="CA_d">Calendar entry</string>
<string name="CA_e">Provides the current calendar event(s) from the selected calendar(s).</string>
<string name="CR_d">Cellular roaming</string>
<string name="CR_e">Provides the roaming status (0 if not roaming, 1 if roaming).</string>
<string name="CD_d">Cellular Data connected</string>
<string name="CD_e">Provides the status of GPRS (0 if off, 1 is on).</string>
<string name="CS_d">Cellular signal strength in dBm</string>
<string name="CS_e">Provides the strength of the cellular signal in dBm with -113dBm meaning \'no signal\'.</string>
<string name="CB_d">Cellular signal strength in bar</string>
<string name="CB_e">Provides the strength of the cellular signal in number of bars.</string>
<string name="CI_d">Cell identifier</string>
<string name="CI_e">Provides the current cell identifier as given by the mobile operator.</string>
<string name="CL_d">Location Area Code</string>
<string name="CL_e">Provides the current location area code as given by the mobile operator.</string>
<string name="CC_d">Mobile Country Code</string>
<string name="CC_e">Provides the current mobile country code as given by the mobile operator.</string>
<string name="EB_d">Event button widget</string>
<string name="EB_e">Provides event descriptions annotated by the user through the Event Widget.</string>
<string name="ET_d">Shared text</string>
<string name="ET_e">Provides text shared to AIRS from any application that allows it.</string>
<string name="GO_d">GPS longitude</string>
<string name="GO_e"></string>
<string name="GL_d">GPS latitude</string>
<string name="GL_e"></string>
<string name="GA_d">GPS altitude</string>
<string name="GA_e"></string>
<string name="GI_d">GPS info</string>
<string name="GI_e">Provides a combined Long:Lat:Alt string for GPS.</string>
<string name="GC_d">GPS course</string>
<string name="GC_e">Provides the heading based on GPS with 0 degrees being North.</string>
<string name="GS_d">GPS speed</string>
<string name="GS_e">Provides speed in meters-per-second based on GPS.</string>
<string name="HP_d">Pulse</string>
<string name="HP_e">Provides heart rate/pulse through the Zephyr HxM monitor.</string>
<string name="HI_d">Instant speed</string>
<string name="HI_e">Provides speed in meter-per-second through the Zephyr HxM monitor.</string>
<string name="HL_d">Device battery level</string>
<string name="HL_e">Provides the battery level of the Zephyr HxM monitor.</string>
<string name="MW_d">Watched media folder</string>
<string name="MW_e">Provides filenames of media newly created within the pre-defined folder, such as for detecting snapshots taken.</string>
<string name="MO_d">Mood button widget</string>
<string name="MO_e">Provides mood as selected or created by the user through the Mood Widget.</string>
<string name="MP_d">Currently playing</string>
<string name="MP_e">Provides information about the music playing (artist:album:track).</string>
<string name="MA_d">Current Artist</string>
<string name="MA_e">Provides artist for the current music track.</string>
<string name="ML_d">Current Album</string>
<string name="ML_e">Provides album name for the current music track.</string>
<string name="MT_d">Current Track</string>
<string name="MT_e">Provides name for the current music track.</string>
<string name="NO_d">Notification</string>
<string name="NO_e">Provides information on notifications from Skype and Google Hangout.</string>
<string name="AZ_d">Azimuth</string>
<string name="AZ_e">Provides the phone\'s azimuth - the angle towards the magnetic pole.</string>
<string name="PI_d">Pitch</string>
<string name="PI_e">Provides the phone\'s rotation angle on the short axis relative to when laying flat and upward facing.</string>
<string name="RO_d">Roll</string>
<string name="RO_e">Provides the phone\'s rotation angle on the long axis relative to when laying flat and upward facing.</string>
<string name="PR_d">Proximity</string>
<string name="PR_e">Provides proximity of any object towards the phone\'s front (usually upper side of) screen.</string>
<string name="LI_d">Ambient Light</string>
<string name="LI_e">Provides the light intensity as measured by the phone\'s sensor.</string>
<string name="PU_d">Ambient Pressure</string>
<string name="PU_e">Provides the atmospheric pressure as measured by the phone\'s sensor (if available).</string>
<string name="PD_d">Step Count</string>
<string name="PD_e">Provides the step count for the recording day.</string>
<string name="TM_d">Ambient Temperature</string>
<string name="TM_e">Provides the ambient temperature measured by phone\'s sensor (if available).</string>
<string name="HU_d">Ambient rel. Humidity</string>
<string name="HU_e">Provides the ambient relative humidity measured by phone\'s sensor (if available).</string>
<string name="RD_d">Random number</string>
<string name="RD_e">Provides a random value, mainly used for testing purpose.</string>
<string name="BA_d">Battery Level</string>
<string name="BA_e">Provides the phone battery level.</string>
<string name="BV_d">Battery Voltage</string>
<string name="BV_e">Provides the phone battery voltage.</string>
<string name="BC_d">Battery charging</string>
<string name="BC_e">Provides the phone battery charging status (0-if not charging; 1-if charging).</string>
<string name="BM_d">Battery Temperature</string>
<string name="BM_e">Provides the phone battery temperature.</string>
<string name="RM_d">Memory available</string>
<string name="RM_e">Provides the phone\'s available memory.</string>
<string name="SC_d">Screen on/off</string>
<string name="SC_e">Provides the phone\'s screen status (0-off, 1-on).</string>
<string name="HS_d">Headset plug state</string>
<string name="HS_e">Records if anything is plugged in into the headset plug.</string>
<string name="IC_d">Incoming Call</string>
<string name="IC_e">Provides information about an incoming call: phone number and contact name (if in phonebook).</string>
<string name="OC_d">Outgoing Call</string>
<string name="OC_e">Provides information about an outgoing call: phone number and contact name (if in phonebook).</string>
<string name="SR_d">Received SMS</string>
<string name="SR_e">Provides information about a received sms: phone number, contact name (if in phonebook) and message.</string>
<string name="SS_d">Sent SMS</string>
<string name="SS_e">Provides information about a sent sms: phone number, contact name (if in phonebook) and message.</string>
<string name="TR_d">Running tasks</string>
<string name="TR_e">Provides currently running applications on the phone.</string>
<string name="TV_d">Visible tasks</string>
<string name="TV_e">Provides currently running applications on the phone requiring user interactions.</string>
<string name="TE_d">Recording template</string>
<string name="TE_e">Provides the current AIRS recording template.</string>
<string name="TZ_d">Timezone</string>
<string name="TZ_e">Provides the current timezone offset in relation to UTC.</string>
<string name="VT_d">Temperature [C]</string>
<string name="VT_e">Provides the Celsius temperature as obtained from external web server.</string>
<string name="VF_d">Temperature [F]</string>
<string name="VF_e">Provides the Fahrenheit temperature as obtained from external web server.</string>
<string name="VH_d">Humidity</string>
<string name="VH_e">Provides the humidity as obtained from external web server.</string>
<string name="VC_d">Weather Conditions</string>
<string name="VC_e">Provides a summarized weather info as obtained from external web server.</string>
<string name="VW_d">Wind</string>
<string name="VW_e">Provides the wind speed as obtained from external web server.</string>
<string name="VI_d">Combined Weather info</string>
<string name="VI_e">Provides a combined weather info as obtained from external web server.</string>
<string name="WF_d">WLAN info</string>
<string name="WF_e">Provides combined info about available WiFis.</string>
<string name="WI_d">WLAN SSID</string>
<string name="WI_e">Provides SSIDs of available WiFis.</string>
<string name="WM_d">WLAN MAC address</string>
<string name="WM_e">Provides MAC addressed of available WiFis.</string>
<string name="WS_d">Signal strength</string>
<string name="WS_e">Provides signal strength info of available WiFis.</string>
<string name="WC_d">WLAN connected</string>
<string name="WC_e">Provides status information (1 if phone is connected to a WiFi).</string> 

<!-- activity labels -->
<string name="AIRS_Timeline">AIRS Timeline</string>
<string name="AIRS_Mood_Selector">AIRS Mood Selector</string>
<string name="AIRS_Event_Selector">AIRS Event Selector</string>
<string name="AIRS_Heartrate">AIRS Heartrate</string>
<string name="AIRS_BloodPressure">AIRS Blood Pressure</string>
<string name="AIRS_Preferences">AIRS Preferences</string>
<string name="AIRS_Events">AIRS Events</string>

<!-- mood labels -->
<string name="Very_Happy">Very Happy</string>
<string name="Happy">Happy</string>
<string name="Feeling_Good">Feeling Good</string>
<string name="Positively_Excited">Positively Excited</string>
<string name="Confused">Confused</string>
<string name="Anxious">Anxious</string>
<string name="Doubtful">Doubtful</string>
<string name="Not_Sure">Not Sure</string>
<string name="Upset">Upset</string>
<string name="Not_Happy">Not Happy</string>
<string name="Annoyed">Annoyed</string>
<string name="Shocked">Shocked</string>
<string name="Tired">Tired</string>
<string name="Sad">Sad</string>
<string name="Very_Sad">Very Sad</string>
<string name="Angry">Angry</string>
<string name="Ashamed">Ashamed</string>
<string name="Bored">Bored</string>
<string name="Disappointed">Disappointed</string>
<string name="Embarrassed">Embarrassed</string>
<string name="Giggly">Giggly</string>
<string name="Scared">Scared</string>
<string name="Sick">Sick</string>
<string name="Sleepy">Sleepy</string>
<string name="Staring">Staring</string>
<string name="Surprised">Surprised</string>
<string name="Worried">Worried</string>

<!-- visualisation tab -->
<string name="Get_storica">Get Storica!</string>
<string name="Storica_description">In addition to the short-term visualisations in AIRS, you can process and visualise your AIRS data with engaging multimedia graphics, using our Storica app. Click on the image below to go to the Playstore!</string>

<string name="WhatsNew2" translatable="false">What\'s new in AIRS?</string>
<string name="WhatsNew" translatable="false">
We improved the sensor handler teardown procedures and re-wrote the phone sensor handler. We also added an explicit EXIT button to the measurement window for faster exit of local recording.
</string>
<string name="ReleaseNotes"  translatable="false">
\n-----------------------------
\n<b>ReleaseNotes:</b>
\n\n
V2.7.9.5:\n
- addressed bug in phone sensor handler\n\n
V2.7.9.4:\n
- improved sensor handler teardown procedures\n
- re-wrote phone sensor handler\n
- added explicit EXIT button to measurement window for faster exit of local recording\n\n
V2.7.9.3:\n
- address bug in template selection\n
- improve DB admin menu\n\n
V2.7.9.2:\n
- improvements to naming settings for media folder watcher\n
- properly support daylight saving time offset for TZ sensor\n\n
V2.7.9.1:\n
- improved checking of GPS availability\n
- bugfixes\n\n
V2.7.9:\n
- removed bug that limited Zephyr readings to 127 max!\n
- restart AIRS recording when updated while recording\n
- improvements to BT discovery sensors (BT, BN)\n\n
V2.7.8:\n
- fixed broken LED notification when recording\n\n
V2.7.7:\n
- added PD sensor as step counter for those phones (e.g., Nexus 5) that have this feature\n\n
V2.7.6:\n
- bugfix for Google account verification when setting in general preferences\n\n
V2.7.5:\n
- bugfix for TZ sensor when starting in timezone different from GMT+0\n\n
V2.7.4:\n
- introduced TZ sensor for current timezone, updated with every timezone update\n\n
V2.7.3:\n
- escape mood and event annotations properly\n
- add setting for upload directory\n
- bugfix for regular upload\n\n
V2.7.2:\n
- check in manual sync if background uploading is selected (can only either)\n
- updated manifest for new Google Play Services (needs to be installed!)\n
- improved SS sensor\n
- ensure that only one file is uploaded to GDrive\n\n
V2.7.1:\n
- small bugfixes in SS (SMS sent) sensor and MO (mood) description\n\n
V2.7:\n
- added option of regular upload of recording files to Google Drive\n
- add Storica user notes to sync files, if those exist\n
- check SS sensor now with timestamp rather than status - hopefully more reliable!\n
- BACK key in manual view now goes back in webview (if inside the manual), not back in activity!\n\n
V2.6.4:\n
- improved selection of camera path by picking camera image from gallery to determine path\n
- use separate icon for shortcuts\n\n
V2.6.3:\n
- improved SS sensor by only recording SMS sent that have been delivered\n
- repaired NO sensor, including recordings from Spotify\n
- fixed check for deleted GI/MW sensors\n\n
V2.6.2:\n
- changed sensor selection with explanatory information for every sensor\n
- sensor list now multi-lingual, including the new explanatory information\n
- changed LED color setting into simple list selection\n\n
V2.6.1.2:\n
- signal start/stop of AIRS via AIRS intent for our AIRS ruler release\n\n
V2.6.1.1:\n
- updated notification bar icons to proper sizes\n
- updated LED notification to re-use existing notification being shown; avoids strange notification when unlocking phone!\n\n
V2.6.1:\n
- enforce timestamp format for sync files with GMT+0x00 format (caused problems in Android 4.3)\n\n
V2.6:\n
- changed LED notification when AIRS is running, avoiding future notification service problems\n
- added AIRS intents, sending recorded values as system intents allowing for listening apps to react upon them (such as a rules engine we are working on)\n\n
V2.5.9.1:\n
- only accept location updates of accuracy defined by user\n
- refinements to lifelogging template, enabling network location by default (in addition to GPS)\n\n
V2.5.9:\n
- change in Location settings, providing now a list of most visited WiFi APs in the last week/month\n
- bugfix in Spotify notication recordings\n\n
V2.5.8.1:\n
- bugfix in automatic configuration function\n
- bugfix in shortcut creation\n\n
V2.5.8:\n
- changed from old Google Talk to Hangout support in NO sensor\n
- extended also map view to full day viewing\n
- added support for automatically configuring AIRS from other apps\n\n
V2.5.7.2:\n
- improve timeline view for teasing richer visualisations similar to those in Storica\n
- add menu to rate AIRS in the market - please do!\n
- improve situations where recordings cross midnight\n
- improve multilingual support\n\n
V2.5.7.1:\n
- add lifelogging template upon first start\n
- updated getting started instructions\n\n
V2.5.7:\n
- added ET sensor for sharing text data to AIRS (such as links from your browser) as an annotation\n
- added TM (ambient temperature) and HU (ambient humidity) sensors for those phones that support it (Galaxy S4 should) although I could not test it!\n
- adjusted weather API to new URL\n
- added Getting Started dialog for first time instructions\n\n
V2.5.6.4:\n
- addressed wrong location reading at (-1,-1) in GPS handler when starting in adaptive GPS mode\n
- removed CAMERA permission (since IH sensor is not supported anymore)\n\n
V2.5.6.3:
- change mood icon in event annotation according to mood being chosen\n
- add spotify tracks to MP/MA/MT sensors (no album information is given by Spotify!) - need to enable the AIRS notification service!\n
- improved GPS handler\n
- check GI/MW for being deleted in Storica and re-inserting table entries properly\n\n
V2.5.6.2:\n
- improve MA/MT/ML readings\n
- do not create downloaded templates if there is a download error\n
- can now add WiFis to adaptive GPS list without needing to save templates all the time\n\n
V2.5.6.1:\n
- improvements in reconnecting to Zephyr monitor\n
- improvements in music player handler in recognising false readings\n\n
V2.5.6:\n
- allow for using system path for camera watcher\n
- improved heart rate monitor through low/high value filter\n
- new icons for mood\n
- more moods being supported now!\n
- can select mood right from annotation selection window!\n\n
V2.5.5:\n
- removed IH sensor (it just did not work well enough)\n
- added BP sensor through blood pressure widget (based on self-annotation)\n
- added averaging window for HP/HI sensors to smoothen values and reduce recordings (define in settings)\n
- properly escape SMS characters now for SQL compliance\n\n
V2.5.4:\n 
- bugfix in shortcut starting\n
- support selecting icon for own moods\n
- bugfix in wifi handler\n\n
V2.5.3.2:\n
- improved adaptive GPS, re-scanning when disconnecting from WiFi (cutting down GPS switch times)\n
- removed usage of GPS from weather handler (network location suffices)\n
- properly support special "'" character in mood and event descriptions\n
- bugfix in location handler UI\n\n
V2.5.3.1:\n 
- fixed bug in location handler UI\n
- fixed bug testing if AIRS is running when starting shortcut\n\n
V2.5.3:\n
- adaptive GPS suspends GPS when near WiFi SSIDs that you can define\n
- improved WiFi handler with better semaphore handling\n
- WiFi returns empty readings when switched off during recording\n
- now checks if shortcut preference file exists\n
- added German translation\n\n
V2.5.2:\n
- bugfixes\n\n
V2.5.1:\n
- internationalised AIRS for language support\n
- bugfixes\n\n
V2.5:\n
- changed UI to make configuration faster and integrate templates better\n 
- added template download from remote server\n
- sync now simplified (single file only) with ability to set sync date\n
- added BD sensor for list of BT devices connected at any moment\n
- added TE sensor for template used for recording\n
- changed Wifi handler to return empty readings if no WiFi is found\n
- fixed bug in AZ, RO, PI sensors\n
- added ability for sensors to disappear in failure cases (e.g., if connection to heart monitor failed)\n
- show template being used in measurement window\n\n
V2.4.1:\n
- bugfixes in managing templates\n\n
V2.4:
- support for templates. You can now save the entire settings (including recording selections) into 
  named templates and create shortcut from these templates - great for travel vs home vs battery-saving scenarios\n
- introduced NO sensor for IM notifications (currently Skype and GTalk), using an accessibility service for this. 
  You will need to enable the service manually in the system settings.\n
- many bugfixes, in particular related to AIRS shutdown, now cleaner!\n\n
V2.3:\n 
- replaced support for AliveTech ECG monitor with support for Zephyr HxM BT heart rate monitor (pulse and instant speed supported)\n
- improvements to TV sensor in filtering the main visible app\n
- improvement to IH sensor\n
- removed PS sensor\n
- fixed erroneous GPS after shutdown\n
- changed settings (check online manual) to group a bit more logically\n\n
V2.2.9.5:\n
- improvements to media watcher\n
- introduction of TV sensor of visible processes\n\n
V2.2.9.4:\n 
- made more features not required to include more devices in PlayStore\n
- bug fix in BT handler\n
- redone widgets to fit single cell\n\n
V2.2.9.3:\n 
- bugfixes in DB handling\n\n
V2.2.9.2:\n
- added DB admin menu\n
  - includes indexing, allowing for creating timestamp index to speed up your visualisations (increasing your DB by about 60%)\n
- fixed bug in remote sensing reminder\n\n
V2.2.9.1:
- improved audio handler polling\n
- removed camera as required feature\n\n
V2.2.9:
- added pulse handler, using the camera for determining pulse. You will need to add the AIRS heart rate widget to your launcher screen to start the heart rate measurement!\n
- improved BT beacon shutdown\n\n
V2.2.8.1:\n
- keep keyguard locked after selecting lockscreen widgets\n\n
V2.2.8:\n
- added lockscreen widget support for Android 4.2\n
- preview of widgets now shown when added\n
- changed dialog window for widgets to full screen\n\n
V2.2.7.4:\n
- bugfix in event annotation handler, selecting the wrong entry\n\n
V2.2.7.3:\n
- add sharing capability for media snapshots (MW sensor) when long-clicking in the measurement window\n\n
V2.2.7.2:\n
- bugfix in timeline/mapview visualisation\n\n
V2.2.7.1:\n
- corrected internal database structures\n
- improved timing in BT handler\n
- sped up historical views\n\n
V2.2.7:\n
- improved weather provider connectivity check\n
- improved handler resource handling\n\n
V2.2.6.9:\n
- bugfixes\n
- allow for sorting event annotations in selection window (enable in event button UI settings)\n
- hold wake lock during sync so that it will not fall asleep when sync takes longer\n\n
V2.2.6.8:\n
- bugfixes\n\n
V2.2.6.7:\n
- remove entry in event (annotation) list of the event widget window by long clicking on it\n\n
V2.2.6.6:\n
- sped up synchronization of local recording (now much faster!)\n
- bug fix in synchronization where applying homescreen shortcuts overwrote sync timestamp in persistent storage!\n\n
V2.2.6.5:\n
- WiFi wakelock now properly implemented (only locked when WiFi sensors enabled)\n\n
V2.2.6.4:\n
- check if AIRS is running when creating a shortcut for your homescreen\n\n
V2.2.6.3:\n
- changed weather provider to worldweatheronline.com since Google stopped its weather API!\n\n
V2.2.6.2:\n
- added back/forward to Manual tab for easier navigation\n\n
V2.2.6.1:\n
- add link to AIRS blog to menu in Manual tab of main UI\n
- now store preferences with each Quick Start shortcut -> allows for recording templates!\n\n
V2.2.6:\n
- backup and restore recording database to/from SD card\n\n
V2.2.5.4: \n
- address bug in calendar selection on Honeycomb\n\n
V2.2.5.3:\n
- create DB now, if necessary (hopefully avoiding force close for recording)\n\n
V2.2.5.2:\n 
- address JB issue of creating tmp picture files\n 
- bugfix\n\n
V2.2.5.1:\n
- bugfix causing AIRS to crash during startup below API 14\n\n
V2.2.5:\n
- added SS sensor for storing sent SMSs\n\n
V2.2.4.5:\n
- bugfix in DB handling\n\n
V2.2.4.4:\n
- improved thread safety of DB handling\n\n
V2.2.4.3:\n
- improved handling of orientation change\n
- bugfix for calendar and general startup\n\n
V2.2.4.2:\n
- added CA calendar sensor now for GB, too!\n\n
V2.2.4.1:\n
- check for V11 SDK when calling Calendar preferences to avoid crash on GB\n\n
V2.2.4:\n
- point to dalore.me.uk for the online manual\n
- added CA sensor for calendar events (requires new permission!)\n\n
V2.2.3:\n
- minor bug fix\n\n
V2.2.2:\n
- minor bug fixes and improvements\n
- sync now works properly with Bluetooth and Google Drive\n\n
V2.2.1:\n
- removed sharing option when exiting AIRS local recording\n\n
V2.2:\n
- changed to SQLlite for storing local recordings (more secure since it does not expose recording files)\n
- synchronization now as menu item in local recording tab\n
- synchronization creates local recording files on the spot (can be kept in /AIRS_temp) with size as set in general settings\n
- widget icons changed, now with translucent border\n
- VI sensor now shown on mapview\n\n
V2.1.3:\n
- make showing of remote tab optional\n
- optional telephony feature allows for installing on wifi-only devices now\n\n
V2.1.2:\n
- added path to map view\n\n
V2.1.1:\n
- added menu with satellite/map view switch to GPS traces\n\n
V2.1:\n
- changed UI to tabbed layout\n
- enable direct start of local recording, in addition to selecting sensors before starting\n
- now support portrait/landscape orientation\n
- merged general and handler settings into single menu\n
- added viewing of online manual in separate tab\n
- enable start of AIRS UI even if service is running (e.g., for sync\'ing)\n
- allow sync\'ing while running (excludes current recording from sync\'ing)\n
- added buttons to map view for animating into current or last recorded location\n\n
V2.0.6:\n
- now show current location in map view\n\n
V2.0.5:\n
- added right permission for controlling A-GPS data download (option in General Settings)\n\n
V2.0.4:\n
- deprecated AA sensor in favour of new AS sensor (sound pressure level)\n\n
V2.0.3:\n
- changed AA sensor to measure sound pressure level in dB now\n
- added sound pressure adjustment setting in preferences\n
- improved AA sensing through native log10 method\n\n
V2.0.2:\n
- show different marker for and focus on last position\n
- save zoom level for map view\n\n
V2.0.1:\n
- improved mapview (now showing the time of measurement for each marker)\n
- improved axis for timeline\n\n
V2.0:\n
- support historical views for local measurements\n
- added timeline historical views for local measurements\n
- added historical map view for GI measurement\n\n
V1.9.7.4:\n
- removed bug that rendered GPS useless since V1.9.7.2 update\n\n
V1.9.7.3:\n
- improved BT beacon handler\n
- corrected shutdown of remote sensing\n
- added warning when starting remote sensing\n\n
V1.9.7.2:\n
- added option for force AGPS refresh on phones that support this\n\n
V1.9.7.1:\n
- corrected \'null\' playlist entry in MP sensor\n\n
V1.9.7:\n
- added watched media folder support\n\n
V1.9.6.4:\n 
- checked AIRS with lint tool to optimize\n
- addressed bug in remote sensing\n
- added delay in BT sensing to give BT time to fire up\n
- use persistent storage to remember music player info to avoid false sensing\n\n
V1.9.6.3:\n
- fixed bug in event button selection, not showing the last selected event\n\n
V1.9.6.2:\n
- measurement activities and widget selectors now work both in landscape and portrait orientation\n\n
V1.9.6.1:\n
- shortcut now directly starts AIRS local with last preferences\n\n
V1.9.6:\n
- added ability to create shortcut on homescreen for faster start\n
- sensor list is now alphabetically sorted for better reading\n\n
V1.9.5.1:\n
- caught FC in restarting procedure\n\n
V1.9.5:\n
- added notification light as possible reminder that AIRS is running (with choice of light and/or vibrate)\n\n
V1.9.4.1:\n
- caught FC when shutting down after discovery but without starting local sensing\n\n
V1.9.4:\n
- small preference changes\n
- if AIRS local service is running when AIRS main program is started, requester appears to be able to shut down last started recording\n
- removed some toast messages on successful operations!\n
- added event button configuration to set maximum number of stored descriptions\n\n
V1.9.3:\n
- changed event button selector to only hold own defined strings (up to 5 right now)\n
- added condition to kill AIRS recording depending on battery level\n
- bug fixes\n\n
V1.9.2:\n 
- sync local recordings now working again properly\n\n
V1.9.1:\n
- caught bug in sync local recordings\n\n
V1.9:\n 
- added individual phone sensor checks\n
- added barometer sensor for Nexus\n\n
V1.8.7.2:\n
- added more event button icons\n\n
V1.8.7.1:\n
- updated event button icons\n
- addressed AudioHandler bug\n\n
V1.8.7:\n
- can add semantic of event to EB sensor through selector window\n
- able to add own mood description for MO sensor\n\n
V1.8.6:\n
- caught another FC\n
- added Java file to Github distribution that reads local measurements into MySQL database\n\n
V1.8.5:\n
- caught FC when system configurations change\n\n
V1.8.4:\n
- caught FC when incoming caller is \'unknown\'\n\n
V1.8.3:\n
- bugfixes\n
- changed Rm sensor to Android available system RAM\n\n
V1.8.2:\n
- bugfixes\n
- added BM sensor for battery temperature\n\n
V1.8.1:\n
- bugfixes\n\n
V1.8:\n
- added MP, MA, ML, MT sensors for currently playing song information\n\n
V1.7.2:\n
- addressed bug in GPS handler for real now (sorry)\n\n
V1.7.1:\n 
- addressed bug in GPS handler\n\n
V1.7:\n
- long click in measurement window can now share measurements, e.g., on G+ or FB\n\n
V1.6.3:\n
- added clickable links to About dialog\n
- improved on restarting service if killed by system (it should now restart with new local recording file being created)\n
- addressed bug in Exit and Share function\n\n
V1.6.2:\n
- changed TR sensor to show application label instead!\n\n
V1.6.1:\n
- read contacts (display name) for SR, IC and OC sensors\n
- addressed service shutdowns\n\n
V1.6:\n
- sync menu option that allows for sharing recently recorded files\n
- filter in GPS handler for invalid location changes\n
- bug fixes and improvements\n\n
V1.5.3:\n
- caught bug in weather sensor\n
- smaller bug fixes\n\n
V1.5.2:\n
- repaired network code (CC) sensor, hopefully\n
- improved battery usage of weather sensor(s)\n
- new main screen icons\n\n
V1.5.1:\n
- bug fixes\n\n
V1.5:\n
- added weather sensors (requires Internet) for current weather @ location\n
- paused state in measurement value window now properly shown\n
- layout of main screen changed\n
- show release notes in About dialogue\n
- improved registration of system callbacks; no Android callbacks when not monitoring!
- allow for using wifi and network in Location handler -> saves power!\n\n
V1.4:\n
- can now share measurements before exiting!\n\n
V1.3.2:\n
- corrections to CS sensor\n
- added CB sensor (signal strength in bars)\n
- aligned some default settings\n
- added two more moods\n\n
V1.3.1:\n
- mood selector only appears when subscribed to MO\n
- changed internal structure of widgets -> YOU NEED TO RE-ADD WIDGETS TO HOME SCREENS!\n
- added more mood icons in selector\n\n
V1.3:\n
- added <b>mood button</b> widget, allowing for setting your mood, being delivered as MO sensor with various states\n\n
</string>
</resources>
