<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright (C) 2011, Dirk Trossen, airs@dirk-trossen.de

  This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it
  under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License as published by
  the Free Software Foundation as version 2.1 of the License.

  This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT
  ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY
  or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU Lesser General Public
  License for more details.

  You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public License
  along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software Foundation, Inc.,
  59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA 02111-1307 USA 
 -->
<resources>
<string name="app_name">AIRS</string>
<string name="Copyright">(C) 2004-2006 Nokia Corp.\n(C) 2008-2011 Dirk Trossen
\n\nContact: airs@dirk-trossen.de
\n\nManual: http://dalore.net/DOT/software/airs-online-manual
\n\nAIRS source code is licensed under LGPL 2.0 license and hosted on Github. For more information on license terms, review <b>license.txt</b>!
\n\nSpecial acknowledgment goes to Dana Pavel. Using AIRS for her research work (http://dalore.net/Dana/research-areas) has provided many opportunities to introduce new features (such as event and mood button) as well as improve AIRS in terms of stability and features!
\n\nNOTE that the authors assume no responsibility for any potential misuse of this software for spying purposes. The operation is exposed through notification bar icons in order to make users aware of ongoing recordings!
</string>
<string name="general_menu">General Menu</string>
<string name="settings_menu">General Settings Menu</string>
<string name="handlers_menu">Handlers Menu</string>
<string name="main_About">About</string>
<string name="main_Sync">Sync</string>
<string name="main_Configure">General Settings</string>
<string name="main_Configure_handlers">Handler Settings</string>
<string name="GeneralSettings">\'Server\' defines the address of the AIRS application server (must be public), followed by the port.\n\n
\'Local Display\' toggles the output of sensor values in local sensing\n\n
\'Local Storage\' switches the local storage on/off in local sensing. \n\n
\'Safe Writing\' writes sensor values directly to the memory in order to avoid loss in case of crashes.\n\n
\'Wakeup\' only senses in local mode when there is any other (user) activity, i.e., it does not hold a wake-lock.\n\n
\'Watchdog Interval\' defines the vibration interval for the local sensing watchdog (0 switches the vibrate off)\n\n
\'Debug\' switches the debug output on/off. \n</string>
<string name="LocalAbout">Shows the sensors available in local sensing mode.\nChoose the sensors you would like to record and press <b>Start</b> to record.</string>
<string name="SyncAbout">Synchronize the local recordings, allowing for you to share, e.g., via Bluetooth, the ones not yet shared before.\n\nThe sync time will be stored so that the current files will not show up for the next sync operation!</string>
<string name="ValuesAbout">Shows the current values of the sensors being read in local mode.\nFrom here, you can either <b>Exit</b> the program (and stop the service) or simply stop the display with the <b>BACK</b> key!\nYou can also <b>PAUSE</b> or <b>RESUME</b> the measurement threads (this does not stop the service but halts the recordings only).</string>
<string name="RemoteAbout">Shows the number of values and the bytes being sent in remote mode.\nFrom here, you can either <b>Exit</b> the program (and stop the service) or simply stop the display with the <b>BACK</b> key!</string>
<string name="MoodAbout">Select the mood you are currently in. Your selection is recorded with a timestamp in the <b>MO</b> sensor.\nExit the selector without selection by using the <b>BACK</b> key!\nYou can define your own mood entry in the text field at the bottom.</string>
<string name="EventAbout">Select the type of event you are currently in. Your selection is recorded with a timestamp in the <b>EB</b> sensor.\nExit the selector without selection by using the <b>BACK</b> key!\nYou can define your own event entry in the text field at the bottom. AIRS stores your last defined events persistently.</string>
<string name="HandlersList">Select the specific handler to configure available settings!</string>
<string name="WhatsNew">
- shortcut now directly starts AIRS local with last preferences
</string>
<string name="ReleaseNotes">
\n-----------------------------
\n<b>ReleaseNotes:</b>
\n\n
V1.9.6.1:\n
- shortcut now directly starts AIRS local with last preferences\n\n
V1.9.6:\n
- added ability to create shortcut on homescreen for faster start\n
- sensor list is now alphabetically sorted for better reading\n\n
V1.9.5.1:\n
- caught FC in restarting procedure\n\n
V1.9.5:\n
- added notification light as possible reminder that AIRS is running (with choice of light and/or vibrate)\n\n
V1.9.4.1:\n
- caught FC when shutting down after discovery but without starting local sensing\n\n
V1.9.4:\n
- small preference changes\n
- if AIRS local service is running when AIRS main program is started, requester appears to be able to shut down last started recording\n
- removed some toast messages on successful operations!\n
- added event button configuration to set maximum number of stored descriptions\n\n
V1.9.3:\n
- changed event button selector to only hold own defined strings (up to 5 right now)\n
- added condition to kill AIRS recording depending on battery level\n
- bug fixes\n\n
V1.9.2:\n 
- sync local recordings now working again properly\n\n
V1.9.1:\n
- caught bug in sync local recordings\n\n
V1.9:\n 
- added individual phone sensor checks\n
- added barometer sensor for Nexus\n\n
V1.8.7.2:\n
- added more event button icons\n\n
V1.8.7.1:\n
- updated event button icons\n
- addressed AudioHandler bug\n\n
V1.8.7:\n
- can add semantic of event to EB sensor through selector window\n
- able to add own mood description for MO sensor\n\n
V1.8.6:\n
- caught another FC\n
- added Java file to Github distribution that reads local measurements into MySQL database\n\n
V1.8.5:\n
- caught FC when system configurations change\n\n
V1.8.4:\n
- caught FC when incoming caller is \'unknown\'\n\n
V1.8.3:\n
- bugfixes\n
- changed Rm sensor to Android available system RAM\n\n
V1.8.2:\n
- bugfixes\n
- added BM sensor for battery temperature\n\n
V1.8.1:\n
- bugfixes\n\n
V1.8:\n
- added MP, MA, ML, MT sensors for currently playing song information\n\n
V1.7.2:\n
- addressed bug in GPS handler for real now (sorry)\n\n
V1.7.1:\n 
- addressed bug in GPS handler\n\n
V1.7:\n
- long click in measurement window can now share measurements, e.g., on G+, FB, ...\n\n
V1.6.3:\n
- added clickable links to About dialog\n
- improved on restarting service if killed by system (it should now restart with new local recording file being created)\n
- addressed bug in Exit and Share function\n\n
V1.6.2:\n
- changed TR sensor to show application label instead!\n\n
V1.6.1:\n
- read contacts (display name) for SR, IC and OC sensors\n
- addressed service shutdowns\n\n
V1.6:\n
- sync menu option that allows for sharing recently recorded files\n
- filter in GPS handler for invalid location changes\n
- bug fixes and improvements\n\n
V1.5.3:\n
- caught bug in weather sensor\n
- smaller bug fixes\n\n
V1.5.2:\n
- repaired network code (CC) sensor, hopefully\n
- improved battery usage of weather sensor(s)\n
- new main screen icons\n\n
V1.5.1:\n
- bug fixes\n\n
V1.5:\n
- added weather sensors (requires Internet) for current weather @ location\n
- paused state in measurement value window now properly shown\n
- layout of main screen changed\n
- show release notes in About dialogue\n
- improved registration of system callbacks; no Android callbacks when not monitoring!
- allow for using wifi and network in Location handler -> saves power!\n\n
V1.4:\n
- can now share measurements before exiting!\n\n
V1.3.2:\n
- corrections to CS sensor\n
- added CB sensor (signal strength in bars)\n
- aligned some default settings\n
- added two more moods\n\n
V1.3.1:\n
- mood selector only appears when subscribed to MO\n
- changed internal structure of widgets -> YOU NEED TO RE-ADD WIDGETS TO HOME SCREENS!\n
- added more mood icons in selector\n\n
V1.3:\n
- added <b>mood button</b> widget, allowing for setting your mood, being delivered as MO sensor with various states\n\n
</string>
</resources>
